Hi everyone and welcome to this session
on matching your sandbox environment
database configuration to that of your
production environment.
A new feature we're shipping in 2026
release wave two.
With this feature administrators will be
able to temporarily match the
configuration of a sandbox database
to the configuration of a typical
production database.
This means that developers and
administrators using the performance
tool get developing apps or running
cloud migration projects
can mimic the configuration of a
production database in their sandbox
environment to evaluate how processes
would run in a typical production
environment. To match the configuration
of your sandbox environment database to
that of a typical production environment
database
you'll see a new button in the admin
center for your sandbox environments
called match production configuration at
the top here.
Clicking that button opens a flyout that
explains what this does and warns you
that enabling this action will restart
the environment meaning that any users
that are connected to the environment at
the time you do this will be
disconnected.
And also that
your environment will automatically
revert back to a typical sandbox
configuration after 72 hours.
Once you start this operation you can
track it like any other operation in the
admin center with the operation details
telling you who did this when it started
which would also give you an indication
of when the environment is expected to
move back to a regular sandbox
configuration.
As you start matching the configuration
of your sandbox environment database to
that of a typical production environment
database there's a few things that are
good to be aware of.
First of all this operation is limited
to three occurrences per tenant per
calendar month
for 72 hours at a time.
Once those 72 hours end your sandbox
environment automatically moves back to
a typical sandbox configuration
during the first environment update
window after those 72 hours end.
Um this operation is also supported in
the admin center APIs, so for developers
that are automating um their development
and want to match the configuration as
part of their processes, uh this can be
automated.
And um
finally, this is only available on
tenants that have a paid license type,
including partners that are using the
partner sandbox license.
This concludes this session on matching
the configuration of your sandbox
environment database to that of a
typical production environment. Thank
you for watching.